# María Alejandra Pérez UX / UI Designer

mapb1989@gmail.com

677709274

Barcelona, Spain



im

 $\succ \!\! <$ 

linkedin.com/in/mapb1989

UX / UI designer with a background in engineering. My experience has taught me how to communicate with stakeholders, provide timely solutions for support incidences and design processes that understand the customer's struggles and motivations. All of these lessons have inspired me and have made me focused on product design.

#### **PROJECTS**

### **UX / UI Project at Ironhack**

Stream Pals: app for SVOD services recommendations

- UX Research, IA, Interaction design, UI Design.
- Goal: Offer accurate recommendations for movies and shows streaming services.

### **UX / UI Project at Ironhack**

FixVid: an E-learning app for home repairs

- UX Research, IA, Interaction design.
- Goal: Helping people perform house repairs while saving time and gaining independence.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **UX / UI Designer**

Ironhack 12/2019 - 06/2020

Barcelona, Spain

# Master's degree in Telecommunications Engineering

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya 09/2014 – 02/2017

Barcelona, Spain

# **Electronic Engineer**

Universidad Simón Bolívar 09/2007 – 12/2012

Caracas, Venezuela

# LANGUAGES

Spanish				
English				
German		0	0	0
Catalan	$\circ$	0	$\circ$	$\circ$

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Technologies & tools**

Figma | Sketch | Invision | Marvel | HTML5 | CSS | Jira | Git | Zeplin

#### Soft skills

Problem solving | Adaptability | Coordination | Time management | Empathy

#### **Hard skills**

Prototyping | Design thinking | UX Research | UI Design | Interaction Design

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Social & Beyond (Barcelona, Spain)

Software provider of Smart WiFi and proximity marketing

# Lead Customer Support Engineer (05/2018 – 04/2020)

- Manage the support team and helping clients with any issues regarding the performance and configuration of their access point and routers.
- Analyze, improve and maintain the company's operational processes.
- Homologation, troubleshooting and testing of hardware.
- Write technical documents related to the company products.
- Report, replicate and track bugs in the production environment.

# Support and Presales Engineer (04/2016 – 05/2018)

- Analyze and design WiFi networks according to project requirements.
- Manage customers' project from contract signature to end of installation.
- Provide training and support to customers as required.